Finding Aid for the Gustav Glück Papers LSC.1768
UCLA Library Special Collections
Gustav Glück papers
1898-1956
1930-1956
UCLA Library Special Collections
Glück, Gustav, 1871-1952
LSC.1768
2 linear feet (1 oversize flat box)
Gustav Glück (1871-1952) was an art historian from Vienna, Austria who settled in Santa Monica, California in the early 1940s. The Glück papers contain materials dated from 1898 to 1956 and include correspondence, manuscripts, and research notes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Langsner estate, 1968.
Biographical Note
Gustav Glück was born in Vienna, Austria on April 6, 1871. Glück was an Austrian art historian, author, and student of Franz Wickhoff. In 1900, Glück became an Assistant at the Vienna Kunsthistorisches Museum, and was subsequently promoted to a series of positions including Curator and de facto Director in 1911, and Director of the museum in 1916. In 1931, he resigned from his position and left Vienna for London in 1938. In 1942, Glück moved to Santa Monica, California where he died on November 18, 1952.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of personal and scholarly papers of Gustav Glück, a Venitian art historian. Materials are in German, French and English languages and span the first half of the 20th century. The Glück papers include correspondence and research notes, as well as typed and written manuscripts.
Organization and Arrangement
Materials are arranged in the original order established by the donor.
Related Material
Jules Langsner Papers (Collection Number 1748). Library Special Collections, Charles E. Young Research Library, UCLA.
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Otto Benesch, 1949 June 16 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Fritz Lugt, 1949 June 6 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Fritz Lugt, 1943 November 15 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Fritz Lugt, 1946 April 28 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Jan Boris, 1949 April 30 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Julius Boehler, 1931 August 31 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Julius Boehler, 1936 March 28 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Velhagen and Klasing Verlag, 1933 March 13 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Velhagen and Klasing Verlag, 1933 February 22 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Max J. Friedlaender, 1936 November 2 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Max J. Friedlaender, 1952 October 7 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Edward Speelman, 1946 March 28 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from R. van Puyvelde, 1934 January 27 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Franz Glück, 1946 December 17 (Box 1)
- Letter to Gustav Glück from Ludwig Muenz, 1946 July 25 (Box 1)
- Postcard to Gustav Glück from J. Allende-Salvaras, 1933 February 21 (Box 1)
- Postcard to Gustav Glück from F. Winkler, 1936 November 15 (Box 1)
- Letter to Else Glück from Mary de Wolf, 1956 July 10 (Box 1)
- "Drei ungedruckte Briefe Gothes an dem Grafen Karl Friedrich von Reinhard" no author, Berlin., 1900 (Box 1)
- "Goethes Memento Mori: Ueber seine Sputen in den Kuensten; uveroeffentlichtes Manuskript von Gustav Kuenstler," autographed with dedication., 1949 (Box 1)
- War Rubens auch Bildhauer? by Martin Konrad, 1950 November 25 (Box 1)
- Review of R. L. Hobson, Catalogue of the George Eumorfopoulos Collection of Chinese, Korean and Persian Pottery by W. P. Yetts (Box 1)
- Articles by C.Fabriczy and K. Voll from Beilage zur Allgemeine Zeitung, 1904 March 25 (Box 1)
- "The Art of Collecting: a lecture by Sir Robert Witt", 1956 July 10 (Box 1)
- Written notes and research materials, 1910-1950 (Box 1)